similarsites.com 2019-12-25

# SimilarSites - Privacy Policy

## SIMILARWEB & SIMILARSITES PRIVACY POLICY

[Last modified: May 25, 2018]

This privacy policy (" **Privacy Policy** ") governs the data collection practices of SimilarWeb Ltd. (" **Company** ", " **we** ", " **us** ”) that we use in connection with your use of our SimilarWeb and SimilarSites browser extensions offered on our website and through various browser extension stores (the " **Extension(s)** ") and our related services (" **Service(s)** ").

This Privacy Policy is an integrated part of the Company's Terms of Use (available at: https://www.similarsites.com/termsofuse) (" **Terms of Use** ") and, to the extent that the processing of personal data is based on consent (see below), is a legally binding agreement between you and the Company. The Privacy Policy and Terms of Use shall be binding upon any use or attempt to use the Extensions, including any portion thereof. Definitions herein shall have the same meaning as defined in the Terms of Use.

SimilarWeb is a market intelligence service that provides in-depth analysis of traffic and engagement metrics for virtually any website or app.

SimilarSites, which is part of the SimilarWeb product family, is a service that directs users to websites similar to the one they are currently browsing.

The Company respects its users’ privacy and makes every effort to provide a Service that meets industry standards. This Privacy Policy provides important and transparent disclosures on **how** and **why** we collect, **share** and **use** our users' data, and we encourage you to read the Privacy Policy carefully prior to using our Extensions or Service, and to use it to make informed decisions.

We reserve the right to periodically amend or revise the Privacy Policy at our sole discretion. Such changes and updates will be effective immediately upon the display of the revised Privacy Policy. Thus, we encourage you to check this Privacy Policy regularly for updates, so that you are fully informed of how your data is collected and used by the Company and your related rights. The last revision date will be reflected in the "Last Modified" heading. Your continued use of the Extensions and Service following the display of such amendments constitutes your acknowledgement of such amendments to the Privacy Policy and, where the processing of personal data is based on consent (see below), your agreement to be bound by the terms of such amended policy. In the event of material changes that will adversely affect your use of the Extensions or Service or the data collection by us, we will use our best efforts to provide you with notification through our website or the various browser extension stores.

IF YOU OBJECT TO THESE TERMS, PLEASE DO NOT DOWNLOAD, INSTALL, OR ADD THE EXTENSIONS TO YOUR BROWSER, OR USE THE SERVICES IN ANY MANNER.

 **WHAT INFORMATION DO WE COLLECT?**  
The first type of information we collect is non-identifiable aggregated information which is made available via your use of the Extensions and Service (" **Non-Personal Information** "). We are not aware of and cannot determine the identity of the users from whom the Non-Personal Information is collected. Non-Personal Information which is collected includes the user's aggregated and technical information transmitted by the user's device as follows:

  * Standard web server log information (i.e., web request) as well as data sent in response to that request, such as uniform resource locator used, Internet Protocol address (trimmed and encrypted for anonymization), HTTP referrer, and user agent; and
  * Search engine results page data (keyword, order/index of results, links of results, title, description, and ads displayed)

The second type of information we may collect when you install the Extension or otherwise use the Service is identifiable information, namely information that identifies an individual or may with reasonable effort be used to identify an individual (" **Personal Information** "). The Personal Information is collected and stored only if **voluntarily provided** by you in the following events:

  * Personal Information voluntarily provided by you if and when you contact us, which may include your name and email address, provided that such information will be used solely to communicate with and support you, and will not be shared with any third parties; and
  * Personal Information voluntarily provided through the various forums and blogs available within our websites, if applicable.

 **HOW IS THE DATA USED?**  
We collect your information during your access or use of the Extensions and Service as detailed above. We use your information collected online based on our legitimate interests in promoting and improving the Extensions and our Services, on the necessity of such information for the provision of our Service where applicable (as described in this Privacy Policy) or, where permitted under applicable law, on the implied consent that you provide by using the Services or Extensions, by requesting support, by registering for the Services or Extensions, or through your use of the various forums and blogs available within the website. In this context, we notably use your information in an effort to improve our users’ experience, to communicate with you about our Services, and to further develop, customize, enhance and improve the performance of our Services and Extensions. In addition, we use Non-Personal Information, aggregated with information or statistics regarding user browsing behavior, such as overall patterns or demographic reports, which do not describe or identify any individual user, as a measure of interest in and use of the Extensions and Service and as part of the Company’s market analysis service.

 **HOW IS THE DATA SHARED?**  
We do **not** share any Personal Information collected from you with third parties or any of our partners. However, we may disclose information you submitted if we have a good faith belief that disclosure of such information is reasonably necessary: (i) to comply with any applicable law, regulation, legal process or governmental request; (ii) to enforce our policies and agreements, including investigations of potential violations thereof; (iii) to investigate, detect, prevent, or take action regarding illegal activities or other wrongdoing, suspected fraud or security issues; (iv) to establish or exercise our rights to defend against legal claims; (v) to prevent harm to the rights, property or safety of us, our users, you or any third party; or (vi) for the purpose of collaborating with law enforcement agencies or in case we find it necessary in order to enforce intellectual property or other legal rights.

The Non-Personal Information we collect may be used or shared in any of the above circumstances, as well as (i) for the purpose of providing and improving our Extensions or Services; or (ii) internally within the Company to conduct business and marketing analysis, and enhance your experience; or (iii) with our partners as part of the Company’s aggregated data analysis services. If we combine Personal Information with Non-Personal Information, the combined information will be treated as Personal Information for as long as it remains combined.

We may share your Non-Personal Information with our subsidiaries, joint ventures, or other companies under common control (collectively " **Affiliated Companies** ") solely if and when applicable or necessary for the purposes described in this Privacy Policy. We may share Information, including Personal Information, in the event of a corporate transaction (e.g. sale of a substantial part of our business, merger, consolidation or asset sale). In the event of the above, our Affiliated Companies or acquiring company will assume the rights and obligations as described in this Privacy Policy.

We may also appoint third-party service providers (operating under our instructions), who may need access to your Information in connection with their services on our behalf. Transfers of your Personal Information will be made in accordance with applicable data protection laws.

We will take the steps required to ensure that international transfers of personal data (including Personal Information) meet all requirements under applicable data protection law. When personal data collected within the European Economic Area (" **EEA** ") is transferred outside the EEA, we will take the steps required to ensure that the transfer of such data provides adequate safeguards, and you may exercise your rights, where applicable, to receive information on such transfer mechanism.

 **OPT OUT RIGHT**  
You may opt out of the data collection and sharing process as follows:

  * SimilarWeb Extension: by clicking on the Settings icon in the extension, or right-clicking the extension icon, clicking Options, and unchecking the box ‘Display site rank in extension icon (requires sending anonymized data to SimilarWeb)’. Note that once you opt out, some or all of the Services provided by the Extension may no longer be available.
  * SimilarSites Extension: by right-clicking on the Extension icon, and clicking on ‘Opt out from sharing data’. Note that once you opt out, some or all of the Services provided by the Extension may no longer be available.

After you opt out, we will no longer collect and share your data as described in this Privacy Policy.

 **USER RIGHTS**  
Please note that, unless you instruct us otherwise, we retain the information we collect for as long as needed to provide the services described herein and to comply with our legal obligations, resolve disputes and enforce our agreements.

Where provided under applicable law (such as within the European Union), you may have the right to ask us to delete Personal Information which you have provided to us, subject to applicable exceptions, such as in order to preserve that information for anticipated litigation or demands from a regulator, or some or all of the following rights: the right to obtain information on our use of your Personal Information, the right to obtain a copy thereof, the right of data rectification, the right to data portability, the right to object to processing based on our legitimate interests, the right to restriction of the processing, and the right to withdraw your consent.

To assert any of these rights, please contact our Data Protection Officer at: dpo@similarweb.com or [contact@similarsites.com](mailto:contact@similarsites.com). Note that we may request proof of identity, and we reserve the right to charge a fee where allowed by law, such as in circumstances where your request is excessive.

In addition, you may have the right to lodge a complaint with a supervisory authority, subject to applicable law (as is the case in the European Union).

In addition, the data we receive depends on your privacy settings with the network (i.e., Gmail, Yahoo) and you should always review, and if necessary, adjust your privacy settings on third-party websites and services before linking or connecting them to our Service.

HOW DO WE SAFEGUARD YOUR INFORMATION?  
We endeavor to use security methods and encryption when handling sensitive data (i.e., we handle the user data securely, including by transmitting it via modern cryptography). Unfortunately, no data transmission over the Internet or any wireless network can be guaranteed to be 100% secure. As a result, while we strive to protect your information, you acknowledge that: (a) there are security and privacy limitations of the Internet which are beyond our control; (b) the security, integrity and privacy of any and all information and data exchanged between you and us through the Service cannot be 100% guaranteed.

 **MINORS**  
Children under 13 are prohibited from using the Service. In the event that we become aware that a user under the age of 13 has shared any information, we will discard such information. If you have any reason to believe that a child under the age of 13 has shared any information with us, please contact our Data Protection Officer at: dpo@similarweb.com. If you are under 18, please be sure to read this policy with your parents or legal guardians and ask questions about things you do not understand.

 **HOW TO CONTACT US?** If you have any questions about these terms, please contact us at: [contact@similarweb.com](mailto:contact@similarweb.com) or [contact@similarsites.com](mailto:contact@similarsites.com).
